All right...is...to liaisons I'm hopefully...time.
So, good...I...everyone's recovered from this wave announcers this morning so,
I'm nothing this exciting finances evil has this morning about all the cool stuff we doing the universe when
...making sure you apps can run everywhere and all sorts of different
flavors and devices today I'm going to be talking about microsoft edge...as...
spots and...what we've been doing a tooling space there and how you can hopefully my goal
...guys to walk away of a few things that you'll see...the new and
it's all so next time you're fixing a bug in a website, you know, fuel...internet,
internet...hopefully you can go like hacked there's this little feature hidden somewhere
...twelve...can make my life a teeny bit easier unsanitary a lot of cool stuff they hopefully?
So, firstly I guess a public service announcement...sessions...evaluated I will put up the
q r...the end of the session please scan it your feedback feedbacks
...need a little better next time round so please provide feedback.
So, firstly.
And, the most important thing if you...is one thing at this entitled to a
...ok job is the we have the developer tools you got brand-new...and demos
...can...and stuff and some to talk about extensibility for it but,
we realize this part of...browser key part of that is
...tools...brand new engine the edge engine a highly
trouble engine lots of features like new hl five-one not features are clearly
tooling to take advantage of those features to use the latest the...stuff or whatever basically
...looking at we need to have some great tooling so we committed obviously to making...
the toolsmicrosoft edge confusing analytics watson the best tools we have an
...platform so ok so now...my toll...one
things conveyed...back to the pool has been...or you can...mourn season demos.
So, one thing I think esri attending point for us
with a tools so-if many...use the tools before I eleven here's use the developer tools
and explore before I eleven quite a few people you remember how painful they were like going back
...hilarious things that you have to refresh the dom...updates and stuff like that
...would really build for different generation...browsers like...browsers the
world's moved on a lot of nine eleven we got to turn this amazingly big ship that was
the tools around and...a lot of the tools that we had so you soar new debug a
new dom explore didn't...you of nt text node everywhere and updated
is the page updated but we didn't quite finish taking what we had a ninety-nine nights
...before even and revamping...this new world so we microsoft
edge one much like have a platform is now...you've got your internet explorer would you can use
...enterprise applications it supports active-x and everything you have known and loved about
ie for the longest time and you also have microsoft edge which is almost a new beginning for the browser
...interop interoperable engine fast perform
...into the latest features so within the same thing the tools web essentially...
a tools and going forward like after windows ten what you'll see is the tools
getting better interact microsoft edge
and the same time the ones that we have...eleven windows ten going to say the same
...a bad analogy but they're going to be frozen.
By...then I'm going to saying they're not going to get any worse.
They're just not going to be...I'll go anywhere so the ships can-we cough...have here...iraq on the
way but, we're not focusing on those tools the tools that you have...eleven on windows tenets
...you'll always have along that for as long as that
browsers supported all-new features are going to be...
edge microsoft edge by browser so we add new features the...a latest standards or
...features that support existing standards is going to happen microsoft edge so
...like web development the tools and edge...keeping in mind when you switch
between perhaps we transitioning app from my eleven moving it forward?
So, the next thing time-sensitive context before I go to demos...been most
...told during demos...on-the-spot but,
I've got to most lines to have...context.
So, you...mine's back a long-time ago perhaps the ...to thousand's developing tools
...but...really just coming into existence...are moving away from musing essentially
...everyone ...all of you today still use...double
...code...so that was the only way of doing in the past times
...moved on and browser tools and got ever more sophisticated, you know,
things...the old I'd have to while the words high sakes to five bug of course the
...of developer tools the expanse...the richness in those tools is ballooned
they become from simple...the can log messages by use...stuff like that set
...points inspect styles very complicated...tools the habits how to features...to
profile application...analysis everything the whole shebang...take memory snapshots
...the entire dom and...an accurate representation...running application they've gone from
the sm relatively simple tools to this huge...of tools
...what is very competitive if you look at even like full-blown
debugged like visual studio in fact in the javascript space the...tools have more features
than they have in the javascript of the debugging...boost...things like trace points event
great points...very points...features that simply don't and source maps as well and
...script don't exist in the visual...gaussian...do in the at
...because ultimately only the browsers have investing in
...tools and every browser look as get this every expanding
ever richer set of api set of features says developer
...m of burgeoning expectation of what you get from your tools like it's not like people
...painted of others the not you pay for high-end profiling tools
...ensure awhile ago so when we think about tools and we think about what we do and
...twelve we have this in mind the head this huge set of almost
...interoperable or expected features the cover everything from some examples up here and that's
...exhausted the pretty much shared by all the browsers
many those features represent the eighty percent...most the time things to say you're probably looking
...tracing styles debugging javascript...probably...keeps...your time and memory tool unless you're
very specifically...looking for leaks and which...verified very sorry for you?
There's also...into the vendors differentiate
...but unique so when we do features we think about it this way does
these common set is basically this ever expanding set of
tooling features that people expect...browsers and point first-level
there's also place...unique features that are only in some browsers so
...a fantastic job advice emulation we can...network changes resize all that
sort of stuff...free...for some time has...and whatnot so they're also
...features on our side the unique features that we think about are often around
...I guess real key problems one is trying to find ways for
you to identify your problem and the second one is trying to find
a ways to get your code out of your at...the browse
...and into your editor license ultimately like showman you done this use
...element is miss positions between the style of it and have to copy and paste it back in your
answer right...sublime brackets whatever
...using to make the change more...so things like if you see the
...changes evans interact changes here hardly anyone okay
...people also...also never that feature free is not millions bond
...married for sometime is really handy?
So, we've also like...that tries to help you get your...the browser the other thing we want to is make
...your problems so one features we added nine eleven
...the updates was just my code...the just...definite apples
a few people so if you're familiar with it the basic idea is that your website is
...of tons of different libraries and frameworks and things like that but
...isn't going to help you like this probably very few problems that you encountering a website
...integrate the...happen...not liking even if it isn't jake or you're not likely to be fixing the bug
...query so you want to work around those issues you
...we stepping...j query be confuse compressing staff and step...for your...
code so things I just my code racially only step in things the your code
and not library code and you can tell us was library code by mocking the file.
So, wisconsin's and demos so firstly.
A big caveat this may be dragons lots of...dragons have
...dragons general dragons and arises...so,
I'm doing whole serve demos on project sorry microsoft edge
...just switched my demo machine to do?
So, the first thing I'm actually daring isn't something in the
...themselves but it's like about the tools...enterprise application
any applications imbedded ie so you've got like a
...rpf application...imbedded inside...number application is in...us haitian
...javascript...a locally on a...and a few
...a pretty comments...expression and prizes so one of the things that can be a challenge is it can be a bit of
...those things...obviously if you've got a visual...projects and...
app and host the web browser control...csharp brilliantly but you can't really types
...easily in touch the dom the consul that the your css so
what we've done is made it so that twelve...we collateral choose
...anything is running id on your machine so if it's in a dot...
app if it's...old-school...app...bay and things like that so I've got this
awesome app which is my version of a browser.
...got resize...that bonding click stuff
...this...obviously windows format and if you use the single
...choose a which will conveniently find windows system...to see
also search for...and...system...which is the follow the everyone knows and
loves over...while...easily actually
so launching this was going to do is going to enumerate all the instances of
...regardless of whether...informs app web apple whatever and show you them so you can
connect them from here and this works response and, the first tip of the day is that this releases spots
and microsoft edge that because...user...the best bet for debugging is actually going to
use...twelve choose...just because right now is...need more stable than the.
As...really
...videos running let me just kill that two-bone what's that area.
Okay, so, here you can see I've got my demo page open legislative metro
choose of...from the list and I'm going to kill this area so one of
the first tools that we've been working on there was a difference my eleven is from when we had
a eleven those two tools that we haven't really touched one of them was the network tool and...have one was
...profiler so the network tool and I eleven was essentially the same one...always been since I
...change the colors minimal white and...and three-d effects but now we've got a brand-new tool.
So, if you go to.
In fact...you page and this new tools...is with note mention that
...who's run...tools we build built-in tag scripps we compile
...javascript which is really handy because as developers...google
...in science and bugging a javascript the tool will also eventually be in visual studio
so-if...you builds their own...the...jobs...applications...as
...that ratio you did build those you'll see the same tools and that
eventually hopefully network tool is generally applicable to the network stack like http traffic
...traffic will also be available,
for example,...as you can see how you some fun navigating so let's just
go to the page is already running...one thing downloaded.
What happens to me sorry?
Such...responsive so the network too.
This was marginalize catches up what we've got here is a very
...firstly most of this tool is in that category of tooling that I think most
you be familiar with which is the hey that's like my expectation is you have a
network tool captures data has visualize is has like
timings and stuff like that and that's exactly what this tool
is so you can see here the eventually we'll have is a list of.
Please work now.
We'll have is a you start again.
Service we haven't had...two different views so we have a some...
great scifi familiar with many tools have a single pattern...an overview of all network traffic
and we have a way to inspect each individual item and that traffic so you can look at
obviously details...the all the information response and request bodies and
headers and from enough in this particular build you can also debugged twelve you can see all these tools down
here for okay but when the nicest things about the network tool that's different is always on
my default so if you go to a page.
We started seeing geology twelve so before if you use the actual
to you might have to go to the network to classic scenario...you spotted...network
...download trouble...that...networks was not back because you...on according
...rerun your scenario so now the tools always on which is awesome because it saves you extra step.
...go who.
So, you can see pretty much as you'd expect new modern new I want to things you
try to do is improve upon ...quite a bit as easy to get...
and less time navigating around the tools themselves on the right-hand side you can see we try to show
the detailed information so left-hand outside is always the some review it also contains a pretty
...along here which is the timings and,
the detail each of the types of network data like bid head is all the body
...visualize is obviously hey you can see like the head is you can also see specifically
cookies so if you cookies they also
...one big long string and they all have...encoded
...we...them...different things...can easily see them...the future also looking adding a
...inspector to the debugged south of the tools themselves you can modify these cookies this is just read-only view
...just showing the network traffic is not language temperate have
timing's...this stuff should be...to use a basic network tool you've come to
expect from every pretty much every browser right.
There's a couple nice things that we do like we have some way visualize is if I filter
down to documents...new thing we...have...tools you can see that
...using the same visualize is as we used in the debugged
...means you can preprint so you can pretty print html javascript css
...even json so...thing we get...log
...came back is pretty printing so...much...network traffic so, for example,
if you're interacting with a json and rest api understanding
magnify data use preprint in...looks something like this is...we see...probably.
So, it's at...the same features from the previous version say things like
...always refreshment server is...handy feature because basically what...from
...does is passing along alway for the network stack like hey get me new data so if you have
a...frustration bug where you may fix you...but
that browser still see the previous version...fix because for whatever reason the cash information hasn't
...each tag hasn't changed it's still being valid than ten this button which is on
by default...and you get the latest information.
One of the things that we've done...tool is new is we've added a support for the...format so you
get...archive format is way of saving network traffic.
So, one of the nice things about this is a...persisting all the data is capture the
...disc so that's useful because you can...to bugs you can attach
...everything's is also of a tools built around this format so,
for example.
If I go save this file to the semi disk and click-through.
I can open up another is...michael edges and find?
An example.
And, people in the community have built ...is the...run things that
...slow against it or like a simple...visualize it so this case if we open up as a
textile because this app just takes rule...but...a
...form format let me show you at so this is one-half format looks file looks like it's just
...very simple json and in captures all that recording traffic's if you
have network bug you attach it to your repo and stuff like that you can also...these back-up in
...itself...open unsurprisingly you can also use tools like this and
we can see here is this is just another visualize...data...some people and you can do
...got like plug-in...and stuff like that...basically perform operations on the...look at
it for like common patterns like okay you may...request the same domain...not magnified you'll
css etc...handy features and the network to another and,
also kind of useful thing to
have some time is a download initiated zone use the download
...stuff on a roughly what it is so the one of the...not many no one was the
...of the key problems about the network is try to figure out way of data comes from so like say in this
case we've got this page which has a broken image we try to figure
...would that come from what we can do as we can go to the right version of ftwenty yosemite
...and...that...that's network to the downside of cooling network
...the same time on network tools ingenious legal network html.
So, what you can see is...this is the right things
... it is you can see that like heretofore
...as prohibit discreet but...color-coded and what happens in
...column if you scholes the right?
Is this as where comes
...of hassd element so if I go...my demo properly measures closes down?
It'll tell you why this line information in this case what I've got is an image like I said
there's been an image source tag...the source tag as wrong as pointing to the
as miss typed so now when I...page about tending on the was recording?
What you'll see is there's a bunch of extra information and ...this...this
...column...the...if I...for savy find website
...for four or five hundred or something like that you can...the...outwards
whereas being requested and that took me back to...which is pointing
...you can see from this little arrow here this...new thing we added is a bit of how...coming from
...microsoft...logo very simple thing that exists in the tools to help you get
...your network traffic information which is like a read-only view the datas coming down to your
source code where you hopefully can make your change you know, and,...the issue we deploy?
The other thing in the network to an issue...you go...
Is that we've been working as well on the possum and stuff...that?
There's a bunch of...get out copy and paste things like that if we just
...json thing one-minute hopefully be...sure you pretty printing
...so again pretty printing...now javascript css
json and everything like that really simple to use this cryptic icon and the.
And, that's another feature by the way if you have
actual today you can do control plus and control minus zoom in and stuff so if you have a findings too little to
...you can do stages...you browsing use control plus-minus which
...easier sometimes...magnify so this cryptic...a...and what
...so useful features if...need to try to find and data another thing that's really handy finding
...we have search and the search is across all
...so search looking head is looking
bodies does highlight matching so if you type in my query straying?
Whoops...type you can see it's got...here and...next but
the thing is often envelopes is the matches was on the
...highlight bas here is all blue
...you can jump around and find a separate easy that's useful
volatiles have as ability to sej all contents which makes it much easier find stuff obviously.
So, the next set of demos washing to the...so one of the things that
...skip to the these two...about will look at what is really that core set of features the local
...expect and the other stuff is an innovative things we're adding.
the first one is simple feature...exchange operate points so
...promising the...window...by when what the hell is cryptic...top right so,
there's tool champs...accessible right this...a new...added this
...operate points charges demo...add one this is the trace points for events
...been using coding you've got like a click handlers and like that you want to log something for you can use that a
...point...like consulate long by modifying your...and that one's event
...points if you want to break...a click and stuff like that you...demo in this but since you're
...it...a bunch of events you-can break on is also conditions which you can apply
...nash to just enable and lethal so anyway we add index...
operate point which is this one here and surprisingly enough well that's going to do.
Is going to break the code this handling x hr...so you want to use this and other tools where if
...the response essentially...changed for
...how you do is the nice thing here that's different...a
...and on-scene days...featuring...much?
...unfamiliar by the general a single
stack stuff probably not ok so I have a
speech perhaps the presentation and I'll show you a bit of water what this means.
...so, one of the problems we try to help you in the debugged and,
we've added a lot more...in microsoft edge is that you probably buy a lot of
asynchronous code like you probably have like ex hr time as or event
business so the problem is that something that, you know, you might you might think that
...like a synchronous code...is a really simple example of using x hr is actually a set
a very disperse operations is...awaiting the user input or waiting for interaction from
an external provider so we try to the debug...is not just show you the whole stack of your current
point of execution and...led to that but we want to also show you all the logical
...so you want to show you...like...way
...x hr was sent and stuff like that to help you solve problems like perhaps
ranks hr is wrong because the url was wrong it might be the case and probably the case that
...in the code this handling the response...not constructing url so you can't obviously look at that and
fact-finding that...application might take a bit of time to figure out so we try to show this
all linked together instead go over this and the awesome...point animation
system you can imagine that this is your applications the enticed and miles application we start
...is global code and have a first asic operational ready vehicle adamantly
...so I have been listeners going-to...obviously on dom content loads happens...nothing else
...execute right now until dumb content...happens?
So, this is the first point that we've...is instrumentation microsoft edge will basically logged
has a...this fact will take the cool stack which...this case is just global code
and it and put a stash somewhere and then sometime later
...come back and say hey...content loaded happened to the next stuff the to
do so in this case what I'm doing is I'm taking my buttons has now been in the tree and why
...a click handler again nothing's going to happen with this button just yet and we're going to
...like...operation has been started again is adamant listener has been
wide up and this was the stack...stack now is also global code on the
...event fide which shouldn't be on yet?
So, now we skip ahead and the user
clicks the button and this alzheimer's anybody application so...x hr
...buttons...the affection data executes these things synchronous lee and then again we
...up another event...this time is already say change it could have been at
event listener restate change that both...the same thing in the browser and they get
wide of the same again we take the stack so this...the on click handler communion global since
everything was comes from global at some point later and we now send request a
...point later we actually breaking the debugged so...job...point this is the point where we break
the actual response already there's been three or four steps enveloped this applicator
...up to this hamming so those steps can be very important when it comes to debugging since
for example, might be thinking like how I'd go back and see whether the exchange object was constructed to
...url was...the right parameters and whatnot...that's exactly what you see here.
Is that entire trace so we do this other things not just x...this
...time is so wherever you building an application
...using...events which is probably everywhere there's a javascript
...solves event-driven you should be...the logical stacks these...
stacks is the ability to see these things happen in the past...a long-time ago
not too long ago but certainly didn't happen with the same execution stream so
...a handy feature so in microsoft edge of extended that add more segmentations
and now buttons and...dom is basically fire adamant list
...wide up...much...much more easily
...trace back for your application define what happened?
All right so the next of stuff we've done that about the is really about improving
the source navigation so many people use time...okay if you will coffee scripts.
No, one okay any other like compiled...familiar the idea that hey that javascript
...also language great for a lot of things one thing is almost, you know,
good is typed it has no results from...I was
rehash that the downside of that is a commune very hard to create like clear objects have clear
contracts between different components and things so many people choose to use a language like type
...that allow you to have rich strong typing...a compiler...simple mistakes so if you fat
...it's an...time allows you check for those of things now
...compiling and editing...talking about the debugging side now and
...only the passes...just show you source maps so this is a little
...tracey thing and if I go to you can see in the file
becca I've got my ts file...also logo of course I get all
the syntax classification if I separate points...all expressed
...type script but we haven't taken advantages some of the things that we get...strongly...language so,
the some of the biggest ones we get right now all of added is the ability to
go to definition so here if you use the context menu you'll see two things one is that
...definition find references so go-to definition...so the
...to the...was defined in the case I just one from a type vector...gone to the
instructor but, also means if I go from something like that we find is...here.
And, if I go to definition...jump...is so in that case that was just by two things apart
but what it takes is means is you've got this application got lots of object lots of classes
you done the right thing you've got a strongly type language...at language output...your source maps
...compiled code and you can now the...the used to go to a definition and find
...to navigate so like when you're stuck in a bright point you try to figure out what was this object
...equated
...definition but the reverse thing is also very handy and that's fine references...you
...references it's...better example second what that
...bring up is this little window the bottom...twelve.
Which shows you all the places in which an object is referenced so anywhere where someone said that
valuable use that value?
...I'm giving.
You can easily navigate through.
...application to find out why it's used so...if you
...application like this one is and if you underlines...we have a much larger application that's
really useful allows you to...do some of the things...used to if you use visual studio
by jump around and navigate your source code without a lot of effort.
So, pretty handy feature.
And, again, is trying to take some of the things the of a existed for strongly...languages...
relatives and try to bring them into the in browser tool experience so that when...debugging...
you have a much better time is also was...javascript but find...javascript is a bit flaky
...not strongly typed so, you results will vary depending upon the application if
application is just...one big strengths can be very hard for to work absences working
nod the execution level but it looks your source code sector source code is one
...but then you having so many problems that you probably outlook anyway?
So, yes, the next of things the kind of new for the tool we can quickly do
the consul so one of the useful things...the consul as we
...very simple which is why...key if you press
...we can system of a browsers again like one thing we don't want to is the different...and things like
...been no good reason so in places like for example,...scape
...the consul you can also use the same shortcuts you...like from
if the continue gaussian ff twelve...five is continue but fa
also works so we try to keep...short has the same so when you go-between
different browsers in-between entering browser tools you might have to...many shortcuts which can handy.
But, one of the biggest things we added was betta...have...to code so again this is
...of those common features...browsers...simple code if I just open up is going to the
world's symbolism...application you can see we've just got a simple log statement hours
ago down here and now we have the source location...a...emitting for a long-time
...just say...web message came from so using application your
...the confluence stuff you can now does have a simple lightening they'll take you back to place with a
long came from very straightforward the next thing we also added was not just logging
...just source locations for javascript but if you're using a source...
...on one second and also works for that so in this case I'm also going to type script file and
...making use of ...log...you can see here just about...also comes
the ts...click it and I'll take you to the ts file version of it start ts which has
...class and stuff like that so trying to pervasively use
source maps across all the tools so realizing that one of the things...really help is using these
bridge languages do static compilation stuff like that and try to bring some of the handing
us back into the tools the...debugging.
All right so what when...a similar vein one of things we also did was to added
the dom explore several long-time we've had in debugged source maps
...types...whatever we've always had that for the dom so in
the dom if you if we just inspects and reaganomics...
I've got this button in the middle of...just fantastic but the interesting thing about this button isn't
that amazing it's the used sas so,
you click on this and...file what you see is the sas file.
So, we've got ...you have support for source maps so-if using source...like lasso
...whatever you're using geragos is that's now in the dom explorer and there's these visualize is
you can see the colorized for each language another nice thing is that stuff I mentioned before find references
...also works here so I've got these buttons and this color here and you can...
find references and if I zoom out we that will show you is
that just the bottom is listed all the place that those variables and used
...of may...things allows you do is defined variables...things like colors or anything really and then you can
...application so rather than having to look for ff
...application changing manually to some slightly off white-colored the might be using you
can declare variable the nice thing that allows us to do the tools is a link
those things together so you can do things like you can find references but also if
...a much bigger style sheet you can just do like go-to definition and you can jump back and see ways
...in the code so you can navigate around not just type...a and
...execution like...languages but also around css soaps
fasten mess specifically is a great...using some of...politicians to make better use...
to develop a tools rather than having to your manually...and stuff which is...fullback.
Yeah, and, the other thing if I turned off source maps for this one show
a demo something which is this one here we also added pretty printing
...so now pretty much everywhere...fr...preprint stuff...is
...html or even if I css...html digital pretty...
That's handy of courses you come to use these compile language because sometimes you probably, you know,
we modifying stuff that isn't from a source maps language.
So, the last with...real big change do we made in the tools
was like I mentioned was for the old script profiler we talked about how we changed
the network tool for the last one we did we also changed the
start generating close this we also combines the javascript...into the
...tool so we used to have to tools we have the responsiveness toolwhich is also
...and we also have descrip profiler tool so one of them would profile
h mario css and stuff like that but it wouldn't profile script execution so if you
...execution...see this big...in media...they just said like
scope execution you...to see what really happened...to see the event...it you have...a script
profiler to profile javascript so what we did as we move both the tools...the same
thing as a you can see done this tab here is also your javascript
...stacks?
Which is pretty useful so
...all-in-one place now so like if you want to see anything application
...any profiling just use the performance tool and you get both the javascript
who stacks and of course the...before...analysis and stuff like that?
One thing that's also been added that is usefulto show is that we
added feature one of the problems...tools but you profiling provides
...a couple problems one is they have lots of data have an awful lot of
data and it's very hard to think like what the of actually is this data like between these two
points in time what happened because ultimately...probably profiling a scenario like
writing email playing a game or something some...driven of course the...didn't really understand
user driven concepts understands what platform understands so what we did is
...to common...to standard really api is
...measure the you can use...not seen is before already there and all the...browsers
...basic idea is you instrument your code and you create this array of timings so,
what you can see here is that you say like performance
...mark the start of your scenario so say in this case it's going to do stuff but it
could be anything it could be not just in the same stack but it could happen minutes later doesn't matter you just
a...scenario...someone...when that snares ended you go examples scenario
so...you two points in time you probably want to measure the time between those two things and the
...so-you that's...performance...comes in and in that you just passing the name of it the name
is...and the starts and, measures so you can we use measures this way and have multiple scenarios
multiplemeasures that uses emacs of thing so that's great and
the purpose of this api...you can then logged that your server you take all the data...performance
...you send it back fragile x hr...you can see how while the applications doing
and that's fantastic but we also in the tools of changes so that will also
appear here so you can see the tools you'll start to have a...section and
...you can do you can...just this event and I'll show you what's happening just
...that time so hey you can see the...click which is an event and this is all
the things happen just for that particular scenario you can filter out all the data that was up
...selfless for this particular profile and focus
...just what you one which is useful especially if you have a story that has tons and tons of data
are looking for a specific set of sequence of events?
And, again, also for this is javascript...stack you can see only the things that
happening the javascript world...relevant that particular time
...have a nice thing that we've done to the tools is we've had some integration the dom you can see here
...as I click over things that happen on the dom I have we highlights over in
the page so-if you have a ch meta elements or node in the pef tools
...highlighted if it's...on the page and also have.
Shown comics for button to take you back to the individual thing so you can verify your
perf tool way of tracing...this information and go back to atomic score
...the time you might want to tweak something over the dom side we'll just see with
...was so some better integration between the two different tools get backwards and forwards
the useful things remembers that when you do profiling do try to
...code because that really helps the profiler tailor the information...you
...looking at thousands of reams of events but more just
...meticulous at the other big change in the profiler we moved away from
being...profiler so for this on a step back...eleven for...and,
I eleven one things we had has been has...is weekly
instrumented profiler so the way it works pretty simple every single time you enter function every time you
exit a function we record something and we have this huge...stuff which we aggregate and stuff and present
you data is...in terms of it tells you exactly what happened to the individual
...individual functions the downside is a huge overhead so like you take this is
just a regular page...I eleven...a few times and see what data we get
...the first one to the first ones were slow to the jacked them?
And,...on the open...rtwelve.
We'll see is the perfect goes down drastically.
Ok, so, try again because one of things we do in rtwelve is we turn on debugging so
...at twelve we tell the injure hey...in debug mode now
fallacy impact perf because which highly engine keep...extra information...make for things they
would normally do so to get around this if you turn on the profiler we turn that back off.
But,...can see the downside here is the way
that this application works is the instrumentation which is what this profile
...does is actually much more impacting and even just being
able to debugging so you can see the last result...is when you recording profile data
...thank you magnify and you could break.
Yes.
Okay, so, we can see here the last one with their profile intend on
was two-point-six which is almost double the time while
...was over double-time...with debugging enabled and almost what for
...for times four times slower than we've just regular page the point here is the
...a...profiling has a huge impact on the actual data you collect so
the downside of that is if you're profiling your profile...slower...can lead you to all sorts of weird places
...never looked because especially things that...function has been call-up
...of profiling is pretty bad because they'll just say likethis is your
problem...actually what it means is the way I...the problem sorry so,
what we changed is over naive for microsoft edge...ten we
...cpu sampling...cpu sampling was enough layers that...like every
x milliseconds...every microsecond what does it takes everything's on the stack...you
...a cpu walks everything...on the stack right now logs that so the idea here
is that if things to be statistically relevant they should be on the stack in the sampling interval so the
smaller functions small things that are exist one-b so impacted does
...less overhead so now if I try the same thing?
First...page...doesn't have debugging enabled because that's can...
And,...same time...about the same time so now let me turn on profiling
...the...roughly the same there was never going to be the same and which...on profiling?
...six is about the same so the point here is the
...profiling doesn't have an impact the used to have on application which is
...useful the other things keep in...would in this is that if you are ever doing...data like
...tracing...outputting to the page that I am...outputting comes
about log turn on the profiler anyway even if you're not using the profiler if you turn it on you'll see
...even results will be more representative of what your customers doing because again
...on debugging which have your customers don't do so,
that...impact the trace and the future we adding a...disconnect button
...can disconnected tools and debugging which was at the engine back into his normal mode see
...impacted by this yes that's the first...cool thing about the new profiler says
all-in-one...to be cpu sampled we have user measures so that
...code...specify...points in time.
So, the.
Last...quickly look at the memory tool.
So, the...of tool you use when you have to use
...a...spend much time looking at memory leaks.
Anyone a few people so they can be really painful memory leaks are often this...things the
...by things like...references or stuff like that and they can take a lot of times
analyze and the tools themselves again contain a lot of data we usually take every single object
you've got so if you...complicate action application that's hundreds of thousands of objects which is
ridiculous amount of data so what we try to do andwe've improved in microsoft edge
...more obvious is the ability to the take snapshots so what I've
got I've got a button.
And, I was encode if I go to this code look in the debugged it's a really canonical example of a
...pretty simple leak viewpoint...do...often node.
So, in...try to do is to highlight things that are
potential problems so in this case the problem is that we've got a reference to a node
...the dom so we've got element whatever that...is...it from the...and every
...we still got a javascript reference to it so essentially often from mock-up so,
...you encode have code looks just like...you do is we take a snapshot
...bb press the button to get fest we go back to the memory tool.
Which is running take a snapshot and we should see is a little
button notting that again they should be...highlight...that shows you
cassette ...in this left-hand side botulism...working on left-hand side is
...nation...they'll show you when...lead to node...see those?
That's a good indicative...looks if you use libraries, libraries have like
...fragments they keep off the side and you buy one...if you do have your...code and you can see
...reference...here looked a little like information icon on the left-hand side the other thing that's really handing
the tools do we do is again along the lines of... founder on my
...application the typical again
...the other thing we do is we've got a consul method to try to where you can
...code taken memory snapshot so...for...profiling memory is to
...because you're looking between...from for leaks specifically you take a point in time technical point in time
comparison was different the problem is the ui like you just use the
of tools you have to press a button like the same time you're running application and doing whatever
...to switch the tool press a button to do that so it's obviously not quite as high-fidelity
you might like so we've got this thing called consulate
...stature so you and your code is again when you're scenarios dot you take a snapshot your scenario
ends you techno snapshot then you can...those so if we go use this?
And, if we look at the summary utilize in other places we'll see.
Separate...there is you take snapshots and they appear in this list here so then you can go ahead and
...them the idea here is the
...spaniel code this problem most important tips in terms of profiling is if you
...your code providing much better information into the tools
...spend less time...around and trying to figure out what time
...what time stamping application and how...to measure the end-to-end the scenario?
The other thing we've done the tools sizes open of one of snapshots is much like the performance
to we've tried to...with the dom explore so if I find
html...which I have as many this application you can see...things like
there's the highlighting again so you can see religiously but this object in the object
...memory is this object
over the dom which is pretty nifty again just the other things you can write click shown
...explore go back to the element inspection tool so again
that's probably more the common set...be...those...seen that but it's really nice
...you get from one place your code which is object...backtrack
...application so you can see where the node is your tree rather than just looking at it from the
object graphs side of the house which is funnel.
Scenario back.
Okay, so, I think we're going to few minutes left...yeah.
So, I think but pretty much covers the demos from switch back.
To the slides.
Yet so there's a few things that we haven't done yet we're hoping
to doing future versions of the tools and when...to do this
...an experimental set of features so this will be a separate thing
...separate tab it might just look like something like?
The ads that say where you can enables and features and features
looking enabling is a...jobs...we don't have yet the tools but from enough
...you sort of icio get codes days the same page on...that we use net twelve of
the day off the same common code base so, you want...jobs editing so you can not just fine
and debug issues but hopefully fix them so typos and...by that you can easily fix
...so like today...we have the ability to edit styles by the
...styles views you get this ridge object graph
...can...stuff and stuff but sometimes you just want to edit text and that's really what the edits
is feature is...the edit...the last two things are really abouts inspecting
stated application so today if you use cookies there's no real way of often able
to see what's in your website so what we've done and, this is...five you'll see future
flights don't know what exactly...it feature...selected review way you can edit
...you can change the values to lead them play them...sort of stuff...you know,
you basic...same those...storage today if you having to
catch data and persisted form like an open session of the dom you can
...debug...consul but that's not the most...so what we've got is view is for those again, so,
you can edit immigrate and hopefully...is add more experimental features
...is window-shopping faster and constantly
...faster but you also have things that we're working on actively looking at feedback
is the key thing that really helps us drive what we do esri getting feedback of what you
...you guys need to be more effective more productive and debugging
your websites especially microsoft ad on...on that point the last real
thing...before your time is questions is that we have a bunch of ways to give feedback
...really appreciate any feedback you have...bugs
you see features you'd like to see all just problems we're having even if you don't know what the solution is I would
love...chicken...make sure the...build the best tools for-you right now the
...reach addresses the user voice so...don't see how use voice a
few people vote their like backhoes whenever we do like product planning and stuff
...looking user voice and...where...to the...of things we do next and stuff like that solves
...go-there for bugs for now you still
commando microsoft-dot-com which is where you folly bugs we also have a bunch of stuff the isn't just
...twelve the on gab some of the other things I...do it things like allowing you to
...tools of...and stuff...of course...twitter and...dev tools
to do reach out to us and obviously like just-in-time questions now and then I'll be around
the proof which is on the second-floor just by the cool three-d scanning thing
...that...getting if you printing one-x that if you do...your
...image scanned imprinted...why but the come talk to us?
So, yeah, on that ...and the session evaluation stuff.
So, okay, so, the question.
...the question was you've got...ten machine has microsoft edge has a whole bunch of new stuff like using the
...which has like a buildings...essentially is...how you set up well first
thing is the...ten the vs twenty fifteen ossie was just announced so that's the version visual studio
it has a set of...ten tools for this version ave at the browsers of edge we
doze target debugging from visual studio so if you happen to be using visual studio to build...application
and launch it right now and like the previewing be able to do that without some work-arounds and,
...go see what that's why...launch microsoft...future version you should be able to do that.
So, the question was the asic stuff just...answers no it's for anything the uses
...interval or any the time...like imis...frame if anything use adamant
listener by anything I...in the dom this...and things the on that...of
...those and, then also you can...your own code so there is...that
...show here called debug dime...and you can if you have a library you can
...code to be say like hey I'm starting asynchronous operation...here so if you building
...js we building...you have a
...loop is going and you but your customers just using a promised say
...understand...message...task thing you can...manual library such that will bases the
promise chain they don't see the tasks looping chain which is probably set timeouts...the doing.
I was debug ims facing start operation
and operation in fact we just open up we can find it by...consul.
It's...like it's a microsoft only api.
...use these ones here tracing and our sorry.
Those ones yet...msn augmentation...are use them.
Yes, the question...we...get rid of the major releases we've had like nine ten eleven and,
have twelve I don't know definite my space I do
the for the tools we times just do like incremental updates like in general
apart from the big versions support...change...eleven microsoft edge its
movies like incremental this point so I can't say for...borrow microsoft edge with
a vision pies...says we...them frequently by the windows inside a programming stuff like that?
As a possibly...actually the funny thing is...you...on high contrast
And, then...the tools themselves on...barley implantation is basically you have
alyssa tokens and css it's just not...convertible right now the only way you can get
...high...opt which is pretty extreme if you have...in...windows.
The question was with edge coming to...of debugging that so-you...
game so there aren't going to be the...tools on the phone obviously and these tools one carney
...work remotely so, you abilities visual studio like you can today with
...so today images geo since twenty thirteen...the
...windows phone is a explore it's about essentially the same
it's not in the ossie...nine-a bits that shipped...will be hopefully rem
...be able to debug adj on the...get the same tools
...mention briefly all these tools are actually and I visual seo...which for obvious reasons is not visually.
All right...five-minute early I said I'm going to movement has anymore...questions...thank you.